www.moviesubtitles.org
内华达州 滨海社区
- 早上好 各位 近来怎样?
- 早，奥齐
Good morning, folks. How you doing?
- Morning, Ozzie.
Morning, Ozzie.
我听说他是个什么发明家
I hear he's some kind of inventor.
尼克 吃早饭了
Nick, breakfast.
尼克!
Nick.
- I'm coming.
来了
你的手长大了
Your hands are getting bigger now
胳膊和腿也长长了
Your arms and legs are longer now
甚至你的内在感觉也在长
You even sense your insides
grow when Mom and Dad...
- 韦恩
- 什么事 亲爱的?
Wayne.
- Yeah, honey?
- 小宝宝在哪儿?
- 在婴儿围栏里
Where's the baby?
- He's in the playpen.
他从围栏里跑出来了
He gets out of the playpen.
- No, I fixed it.
不会 我修好了
亲爱的 我不想烦你
Sweetheart, I hate to remind you, but
the last time you fixed the playpen...
可上次你修好围栏
他还是跑出来了
...he still got out of it.
好吧！他这次不会了
Well, he won't get out this time.
嘿 小宝贝是吧？
Hiya.
Will you, big buddy, huh?
修围栏对我来说轻而易举 不是吗?
I'm certainly capable of fixing
a playpen, aren't I?
毕竟你还只是个婴儿
You're just a little baby, after all.
- Your hat?
- 你的帽子?
- 是头盔
It's my helmet.
- New one?
- 新的?
- 对 是新的
Yeah, it's a new one.
看！它能给我刮胡子，看见了吗?
See, it shaves me.
See that?
那儿
There.
艾米 已经决定了，我跟你一起去，不用再说了
Amy, it's decided.
I'm going with you. Period.
妈！首先
Mom, in the first place, I'm not
the first girl who has ever gone...
我不是第一个离家上大学的女孩
...away to college.
其次，我们...
And in the second place, we're...
- Mom.
- 妈！
- 抱歉
就这样
- 想听声音吗?声音?
- 是的 我想听声音
Want a noise? Noise?
- Yeah, yeah, I want to hear a noise.
- 这个?
- 好吧 这次...
This one?
- Yeah. Now, this time...
- 这个
- 好的
This one.
Okay.
- 听见没?
- 是的 听见了
Hear it?
- Yep, I heard it.
- 还听吗?
- 当然
More?
Sure.
妈！假设你是个女孩
Mom, let's say you were a girl.
- I think I can visualize it.
我认为我能想像出来
你认为我很讨厌吗?
我是说 只看外表
Would you think I was a nerd?
Just by looking at me, I mean.
妈！这是个反问句
用不着回答
It's a rhetorical question, Mom.
It doesn't require an answer.
我是某个特定的女孩吗?
Am I any girl in particular?
- No.
不是
只是个女孩或许 我不知道...
Just a girl I might, I don't know,
ask to go to the movies or something.
问她要去看电影什么的
尼克，你已经是一个英俊的小伙子了
Nicky, you are turning into
a very handsome young man.
你会和你爸爸一样帅
You're gonna be just like your dad.
- Honey...
亲爱的
你能帮我调整一下调节器吗?
...can you help me adjust
this servo regulator?
好吧 如果我不在家，但是你和尼克想要出门
Now, if you and Nicky want to get out
by yourselves while I'm gone...
保姆的电话在厨房里
...the baby-sitter's number's in the kitchen.
- 他怎么了?
- 我想是为了一个女孩
What's with him?
- I think there's a girl.
尼克? 我们的尼克?
Nick? Our Nick?
你知道 他已经长大了
难道你没注意到吗？
You know, he's growing up,
in case you haven't noticed.
哦
Uh-oh.
- 我能修好
- 我先修理你 小坏蛋!
I'll fix it.
- I'll fix you, you little punk.
尼克 住手!
Nick, stop.
- 亚当 这不好
- 对不起 妈妈
Adam, no.
- Sorry, Mama.
好，希望你是真心的，过来
Yes, I should hope so.
Come on.
- 哦 天哪
- 你越来越重了
Oh, man.
- You're getting to be a big boy.
你是怎么能溜出围栏的？
How do you keep getting
out of there, anyway?
也许咱们不该把他关在围栏里
I think maybe we should forget
about the playpen idea.
我说了我能修好
I said I could fix it.
I'm not stupid.
我又不笨
我从来没有说过你笨
I never said you were stupid.
出租车来了
Taxi's here.
早餐怎么样?
So what's for breakfast?
Anything good?
好吃吗?
嗯 棒极了
Mmm, fantastic.
出租车会把妈妈送去飞机场
The taxi's gonna
take Mommy to the airport.
然后妈妈会带艾米适应新学校
And then Mommy's gonna show Amy
her new room at school.
希望托儿所能把他搞的筋疲力尽
Hopefully they'll tire him out at day care.
那我回家他就能睡个午觉了
So when I get home,
he'll take a late nap.
不许睡午觉!
No nap.
- Honey...
亲爱的, 我们别在两岁孩子面前说“不”
...we don't say the 'n' word
around two-year-olds.
亚当
好吧 亚当的早餐在冰箱里
...is in the freezer...
保姆的电话我贴在了冰箱上
Adam.
- And I put the baby-sitter's...
...number on the refrigerator.
还有什么事情来着?
Is there something I'm forgetting?
I'm sure I'm forgetting some...
- 我肯定我忘了什么
- 黛安 黛安 放心吧
Diane, Diane, relax.
你认为我不能处理这些事情吗?
Don't you think I can handle
things around here?
你当然可以 亲爱的
Of course you can, honey.
亲够了，伙计们
Break it up, guys.
爸，别担心，她到了那儿发现没什么事可做
Don't worry, Dad. She'll get there,
realize there's nothing to do...
就会马上回来的
...turn around,
and come right back.
再见
Bye.
再见 尼克
快点 艾米 我们得出发了
Bye, Nick.
- Come on, Amy. We gotta get going.
哦 别忘了在你上班时送尼克和亚当
Oh. Don't forget to drop Nick and
Adam off on your way to work.
天哪！时间
Gosh, the time. I got to get you
to work. I got a big test today.
先送你去打工， 我今天有个大实验
- 再见
- 再见 妈
Bye.
- Bye-bye, Mama.
快点 快点
Come on. Come on.
加油 加油
你行的，真是个好女孩
You can do it.
Atta girl.
沙兰斯基试验第1277号
Szalinski test number 1277.
第5组水晶
Crystal Group 5.
我们是不是该等下沙兰斯基?
Shouldn't we wait for Szalinski?
也许这能教会他不要迟到
Maybe this will teach him
to be here on time.
沙兰斯基不是主角，而是我
Szalinski isn't running the show.
I am.
这次最好能成功 所以专心点
This better work this time,
so concentrate.
4, 3, 2, 1, 0
...four, three, two, one, zero.
拿着
Here.
对不起 各位
Sorry, everybody. There were some large
cumulonimbus clouds blocking the sun,
一大块积雨云挡住了太阳
害的我的车失去了动力
and I-I lost power.
还有，我的儿子找了份暑期工
And my son got a job for the summer...
Wet and Wild. I had to drop him off.
我得去送他
你脸上粘着什么东西?
What's that stuff on your face?
哦 对不起 亨得利克森博士?
Oh, excuse me, Dr Hendrickson?
- I'm sick and tired of this.
我受够了这些!
现在, 我们取得了些成果
Now, we have had some success
replicating Szalinski's experiments...
模仿沙兰斯基缩小物体实验已经获得成功
...shrinking matter.
但是颠倒程序，将物体放大
But reversing the process,
enlarging matter...
却让我们一点头绪都没有
...has seen us run up
one blind alley after another.
克利福德·斯特林要求有成果
Clifford Sterling demands results.
他的董事会也要求有成果
His board of directors demands results,
the United States government...
美国政府也要有成果
...demands results...
- 作为项目主管的我，应该
- 对不起，亨得利克森博士
...and as project director, I...
- Excuse me, Dr Hendrickson.
我再和你说一遍,韦恩
I beg your pardon, Wayne.
As project co-director,
作为项目负责人 我也要求有成果
I intend to deliver results.
我自己就这一问题做了些试验 先生
L-I've been doing some work on my own
on the problem, sir.
- 是的 韦恩
- 我想你看下这些计算
Yes, Wayne.
I think you'll find
if you look at these calculations...
- 你会发现...
- 韦恩  韦恩  韦恩  韦恩
Wayne, Wayne, Wayne, Wayne.
当你把设备卖给斯特林实验室时
When you licensed your device
to Sterling Labs, you were promised...
我们保证给你派出国内最出色的人
...that the finest minds in the country
would be working on it, and they are.
我们做到了
- 我知道 先生
- 好 好
I know that, sir.
- Good, good.
但是如果你看这些记录
But I-I think if you look at these
notes, you'll find that although...
你会发现尽管...
曼蒂？
Mandy?
- Yeah, Rick?
- 什么事 里克?
- 是尼克
Nick.
- Nick.
尼克
嘿 尼克 你爸爸开太空船来了
Hey, Nick, your dad's here
in his spaceship. The Dweezil Wheels.
- 好傻的车
- 我们又来了
嘿, 尼克!要搭车吗
Hey, Nicky.
Want a ride?
嘿, 快看 怪车
Hey, look. It's the Nerdmobile.
- Hey, look at that.
哦 天呐
祝你飞行愉快
Oh, man.
- Have a nice flight.
- 真感谢你 老爸
- 谢什么?
Thanks a lot, Dad.
- For what?
没什么
Nothing.
爸！你在学校受欢迎吗?
Dad, were you ever popular in school?
- You bet.
当然
我连任两届天文俱乐部的主席
I was president of the astronomy club
two years in a row.
我们都很聪明
We were happenin' guys.
那么, 你妈说你喜欢一个女孩？
So Mom tells me that there's some girl?
什么?
What?
不 不 我 我只是随便问问
No. No, I was...
I was just wondering.
飞行愉快吗?
How was your flight?
Uh-huh. N-No, fine.
哦 不 很好
不 我们刚到家
No, we just got home.
We're fixing dinner now.
正在准备晚餐
什么声音? 呃 只是电话线路有点问题
What noise? Uh, it was just
a bad connection, that's all.
小宝宝呢? 他很好
The baby?
Well, h-he's fine.
他在围栏里吗
He's in the playpen.
No, I fixed it. He can't get out.
是，我修好了
他出不来
- 冰淇淋
- 艾米的宿舍怎么样?
Ice cream.
- How's Amy's dorm?
很好
Uh-huh. Yeah.
嘿，住手
Hey, stop it.
没什么事，只是狗
Nothing. Just the dog. Uh-huh.
是的，一切都好
No, everything's fine.
你太多虑了
Boy, you worry too much.
什么? 鸡?
What? The chicken?
亲爱的 你留下的鸡看上去很好
Well, the chicken you left us
really looks fine, honey.
我在想正好妈妈和艾米都不在家
So I was thinking,
with Mom and Amy out of town...
咱们俩可以有机会聊聊 呃
...that this would give us guys
a chance to, uh, talk about, uh...
你知道 谈谈男人的事情
...you know, the birds and the bees.
给你 尼克
Here, Nicky.
知道我在想什么吗 宝贝？
You know what I was thinking,
Big Bunny? What?
想什么?
我们应该对尼克多关心点
I was thinking we got to be nice to
our brother Nick. You know why? No, why?
- 知道为什么吗?
- 不知道 为什么?
因为他刚搬来一个新地方
Well, because he moved away to
a new place now, and he's got to make...
他需要结交新朋友,就像你和我一样
...all new friends, just like me and you.
- 是吗?
- 是的
Yeah?
- Yeah.
- 我们现在唱歌怎么样？
- 好的
Shall we sing a song now?
- Yeah.
- 唱什么歌好呢？
- 字母歌
What song shall we sing?
- 'ABCs.'
- 唱"小星星"怎么样?
- 字母歌
How about 'Twinkle, Twinkle'?
- 'ABC.'
- 字母歌?
- 是的
'ABC'?
- Yeah.
- ♪ 一闪 一闪
- 要字母歌
Twinkle, twinkle...
- 'ABCs'.
来唱 ♪一闪 一闪 亮晶晶
Let's sing 'Twinkle, Twinkle, Little Star.'
要字母歌
'ABCs.'
好吧, 先唱字母歌
♪ A-B-C-D-E-F-G, H-I-J-K, L-M-N-O-P
'ABCs'? Okay, first 'ABCs.'
A-B-C-D-E-F-G, H-I-J-K-L-M-N-O-P
现在唱小星星好吗?
Now 'Twinkle, Twinkle,' okay?
好
Okay.
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Twinkle, twinkle little star
♪满天都是
How I won...
♪小星星
What you are...
如果成功了，你可就发大财了 查尔斯
...lt'll be a hell of a thing
for you, Charles, if it works.
会成功的，我会让它成功的
It'll work.
I'll make it work.
这些年来 我看到克利福德·斯特林
Over the years, I've seen
Clifford Sterling attach himself...
想出一个又一个疯狂的主意
...to one crazy idea after another.
我得告诉你，董事会对这个问题很担心
I have to tell you,
the board of directors is very worried.
请稍等片刻
亨得利克森
If you'll pardon me a moment.
Hendrickson.
喂?
Hello?
那是什么?
是气球爆了，亨得利克森博士
What was that?
- It was a balloon popping,
Dr Hendrickson.
我哄儿子睡觉时突然有了灵感
I got the idea while singing my kid to sleep.
你瞧，如果你吹气球太用力
You see, if you hit a balloon
with too much force...
而没有足够时间膨胀 气球就会爆炸
...you don't allow the molecules time
to expand, and the balloon pops.
有问题吗?
Problem?
- No, Szalinski.
没有，沙兰斯基
哦 他
Oh, him.
为什么克利福德坚持让他参与这个项目
Why Clifford insists on keeping
him involved is absolutely beyond me.
要是由我一个人来负责
If I were running this project
by myself right now,
那么我们早就名声大振了
we'd be neck-deep in apples...
...the size of Buicks.
董事会有些成员同意你的看法
There are those of us on
the board who would agree with you.
...原子结构基本完整...
...fundamental integrity
of the atomic substructure...
克利福德·斯特林也许没有意识到这一点
Clifford Sterling just may have
outlived his usefulness...
他对公司、对股东来说都过时了
...to the corporation,
to its stockholders.
我认为他的继任者应该是早就定好的,
I should think his successor
would be a foregone conclusion...
特别是如果你能让这东西成功的话
...especially if you're the one to
actually make this thing work.
...因此给分子足够的时间使其膨胀...
...thereby allowing the
molecules time to expand...
而不破坏原子结构，你好?
...without tearing the atomic fabric.
Hello?
沙兰斯基？
Szalinsk... Szalinski...
干嘛不把你对气球的研究写下来?
...why don't you write up this, uh,
balloon research of yours?
我明天就可以交给你
I can do the math and have it
on your desk tomorrow.
不 不必了
No, that's not necessary.
好吧 周末愉快 沙兰斯基
All right, have a good weekend, Szalinski.
"周末愉快 沙兰斯基"?
'Have a good weekend, Szalinski'?
- 喂?
- 嗨，请曼蒂接电话好吗?
Hello?
- Hi, may I please speak to Mandy?
好的，曼蒂，电话!
Sure.
Mandy, phone.
- 喂?
- 嗨 曼蒂?
Hello?
- Hi, Mandy?
我能修好
I'll fix it.
爸爸!
Daddy.
- Hey, what are you doing up, little guy?
嘿 你在干嘛 小家伙？
嘿 尼克 明天想和我一起工作吗?
Hey, Nick, want to do
something with me tomorrow?
嗯 当然
Yeah, sure.
好的，来吧，伙计
Okay. Come on, fella.
One more story.
再讲一个故事
那明天想跟我和尼克
Then tomorrow, you want
to come with me and Nicky...
去实验室玩吗?
...down to the lab and we'll play?
好的 伙计们
Okay, guys.
看见了吗 亚当 这就是爸爸工作的地方
See, Adam, this is where Daddy works.
- 要我帮你拿那个吗?
- 好的
Want me to take that?
- Yeah.
这事得小心点
Got to be a little bit discreet about this.
什么?
Huh?
- 沙兰斯基先生
- 嗨  史密提
Mr Szalinski.
- Hi, Smitty.
- 你好，你今天还上班吗?
- 呃 只是来整理一下东西
Hello. You working today?
Uh, just gonna tidy up a little bit.
- 哇
Wow.
- Wow.
- 这才是实验室
- 实验室
This is some lab.
- Some lab.
比我们阁楼的那个强吧？
Way better than what we had
in the attic, huh?
- 强多了
Way better.
- Way better.
对 请给我接亨得利克森博士?
Yes, would you connect me
with Dr Hendrickson, please?
你帮我输入下主要激光驱动程序
Call up a command directory
labeled 'primary laser drive.'
再告诉我强度一栏的显示
Tell me what it says under 'intensity.'
- 上面显示拒绝访问
- 拒绝访问?
It says 'access denied.'
- Access denied?
我得想办法降低激光强度
Got to figure out some way how
to lower the intensity of the laser.
嘿 爸爸
Hey, Dad.
我们或许可以散射它
We could diffuse it maybe.
是个好主意
That's a good idea.
现在设定最终目标
Now we'll set final target.
- Target what, Dad?
什么目标 爸爸？
- 借我用下行吗？
- 不行
Hey, can I borrow this, pal?
- No.
来吧 让我看看能不能把兔子先生真的变大？
Come on. Let me see if I can make
Big Bunny really Big Bunny, huh?
是的，先生，我认为他星期六来这不正常
Yes, sir. I thought it was unusual,
him being in here on a Saturday.
你向我汇报是正确的 谢谢你
No, you did the right thing
letting me know. Thank you.
好了 我不玩了
Well, that's it for me.
嘿 你得戴上眼镜
Hey, you're gonna have
to wear some glasses.
好了
There you go.
30秒
Thirty seconds.
25秒
Twenty-five seconds.
20秒
Twenty seconds.
19, 18, 17, 16...
15, 14, 13...
...15, 14, 13...
12, 11, 10...
...12, 11, 10...
9,8,7,6,5...
...9, 8, 7, 6, 5...
- 爸!
- 糟糕！电涌!
Dang. Power surge.
- 3, 2, 1...
- 快点 取消开关!
- 3, 2, 1
Quick, the abort switches.
- Zero.
无法取消
Unable to abort.
乔,你那边怎么回事?
Joe, what's happening up here?
呃，沙兰斯基先生
您的安全等级
Uh, Mr Szalinski.
Uh, your security clearance...
没有亨得利克森博士的许可，你是不能够使用这些设备的
...denies you access to the equipment...
...without Dr Hendrickson's permission.
- 这个您是知道的 对吗？
- 知道 史密提
You are aware of that, right?
- Yeah, Smitty.
呃 沙兰斯基先生
Uh, Mr Szalinski...
很抱歉我不得不...
I'm sorry I had to, uh, uh...
你的宝宝...
真的开始长大了
That baby of yours.
Sure starting to get big.
再见，史密提
See you, Smitty.
我长大了
I'm bigger.
Bigger, bigger, bigger.
长大 长大 长大
爸, 你在自己的发明上工作
Dad, how come you got to ask
somebody's permission to work...
为什么还要别人许可?
这样 尼克 爸爸现在是一个团队的成员,
...on your own invention?
Well, Nick, Dad's a member
of a team now, and I'm working...
我和一些非常有才华的人共事
...with some real talented people.
但是，爸！这是你的发明啊
But, Dad, it's your invention.
They didn't have the idea, you did.
不是他们的点子，是你的！
好吧 宝贝
Okay, bud. Looks like Daddy...
看来爸爸要多花点时间陪陪尼克了 好吗？?
...needs to spend a little quality time
with Nick, okay?
我要给你找个保姆
So I'm gonna get you a baby-sitter.
You're gonna have yourself a good time.
你会过的非常愉快的
- 尼克
- 好的
Nick.
- Yeah.
你好像重了点?
You puttin' on a little bit of weight?
我长大了
I'm big.
听我说 爸爸要给你做顿又快又好吃的午餐
You know what? Daddy's gonna
make you a nice quick lunch.
低热量的东西怎么样
Maybe kind of a low-cal thing.
你认为呢？
一定很棒
What do you think, huh?
It's gonna be good.
好的,你要知道什么?
Okay, you know what?
Sit down and hang onto him.
好的 听我说 坐好抓紧他
让兔子先生陪你一会
我要做事了...
This guy's gonna keep you company,
and I'm gonna make...
哦 保姆的电话，保姆、保姆
Uh, baby-sitter,
baby-sitter, baby-sitter.
555-5654.
好了 午餐
这个怎么样？
Okay, so lunches.
Whoa. How about that, huh?
喂?
- 嗨 是曼蒂·帕克吗?
- 是我
Yeah?
- Hi, is this Mandy Park?
呃，三点半? 好的,沙文斯基先生
Uh, 3:30?
Sounds okay, Mr Schlitzminski.
是沙兰斯基，亲爱的
Uh, Szalinski, dear.
- Szalinski, right. That's what I said.
沙兰斯基，是的，我说的是这个
我每小时收费2块5
I, like, charge $2.50 an hour.
Unless, of course,
当然，我什么事都做
I actually have to do anything...
但如果要我换尿布给孩子清洗什么的
需要另外加钱
...like change diapers
or clean up or something,
in which case, the price goes up.
哦 不 你只要看好他就行了 真的
Oh, no. All you have to do
is just-just watch him, really.
- 好吧 3点半见
- 好的
Okay, see yOu at 3:30.
- Okay.
好了
Okay.
这碗是夸克的还是你的?
Okay. Are these Quark's or yours?
待这别动
You just stay here, okay?
电话里她听上去很不错
She sounded great on the phone.
- I want to go to a restaurant.
- 我要去饭店吃
- 你要去饭店吃？
可我已经做好饭了，很棒的
You want to go to a restaurant?
But I just made this stuff.
好吧 我来当服务员 好吗？
Well, um, I'll be the waiter, okay?
And, uh, let me take your order.
我来帮你点菜
- 你想吃点什么呢？
- 我要吃鸭子
What would you like?
- I want the duck.
鸭子，鸭子，今晚的鸭子不太好
Duck. The duck...
The duck is not very good tonight.
我给你推荐个特餐怎么样？
Uh, can I recommend the special?
- 好的
- 太好了 我们今天有例汤
Okay.
- Okay, fine. We have soup du jour.
有汉堡，还有炸薯条
We have hamburger.
We have French fries today.
- 你想尝尝吗
- 好的
Would you like 'em?
- Okay.
- 好的，我马上回来
- 好的
All right.
I'll be right back.
- Okay.
嘿 尼克 想看电影吗?就我们俩
Hey, Nick, want to go to a movie?
Just the two of us.
好啊 正好有部片子我想看
Yeah, there's a movie at the Desert Six
I wanted to see.
太好了，去看吧，可以让我们忘掉烦恼
Great. Come on.
It'll take our minds off everything.
我查查时间表
I'll check show times.
- Okay, and then maybe afterwards,
好的 或许看完电影之后
我们可以去吃点东西
we can get a bite to eat or something.
大、大兔子
Big, Big Bunny.
什么声音？
What's that?
它怎么了？
What's gotten into him?
爸 怎么搞的？
Dad, how?
- Where were you in the lab this morning?
你刚才在实验室看好亚当了吗？
Were you watching Adam?
他在仪器旁边
He was off to the side.
- But at the moment of discharge,
激光发射的那个时候，他在哪？
where was he?
发射前我看他在推车上 不在吗?
Just before, I know,
he was off to the side. Wasn't he?
我不这么认为
Somehow, I don't think so.
哼
Boo.
别担心 亚当
Don't worry, Adam.
Daddy's going to make everything okay.
爸爸会把你变回去的
好吧 我们得把他带回实验室
Okay, we got to get him back to the lab,
analyse the data...
分析数据 把程序颠倒过来
...and reverse the process.
- 有个问题,爸!
- 什么?
One thing, Dad.
- What?
你不觉得我们带着个七尺高的婴儿
Do you think the security guard might
get suspicious with us walking in...
会让保安怀疑吗？
哦，有道理
...with a seven-foot baby?
Good point.
只能遮住你的脸和头发
This will cover your head and your hair.
Here, Adam, put this on.
拿去，亚当把它戴上
好啦
他看上去像穿错衣服的养蜂人
There. He looks like
a badly dressed beekeeper.
好吧
All right. Okay.
Now just act natural.
表情自然点
快点 孩子
Come on, bud.
Atta boy.
史密提! 我忘记拿钥匙，我的车钥匙！
我没法开车了
Smitty. Smitty. Um, I forgot the,
um, the keys, uh, to my van,
and I couldn't-couldn't start the van.
我忘在实验室了，我也不会动用里面任何设备的
It's in the lab.
It's in the lab, but I'm not going...
...to use anything in there...
因为你知道的，我的安全级别不够
你之前提到过的
...because of my security, you know,
access... a-access thing,
which you mentioned earlier.
所以我只是进去拿我的钥匙
So I'm just gonna get
the keys in the lab now.
亚当
Adam.
快点 下来
Come on, down.
沙兰斯基
Szalinski.
- Go back up.
快上去
我只是路过想顺便
Just stopped by to do
some, uh, computations...
在数据库里做点检查
...in the... in the database.
数据库被删除了
The database has been erased.
Our entire experiment, gone.
我们整个实验的数据都没了
快回去 回去
Get back. Back.
- 删除了?
- 所有38G资料
Erased?
- All 38 gigabytes.
- 怎么可能
- 当然可能
It can't be.
因为你用这破玩意堵住了过滤器
Sure it can, if the main controller was
trying to compensate laser intensity...
想使主控制器减少激光强度 你这白痴
...for this, which you jammed
into the filter pack, you idiot...
造成了整个电力系统的超载
...causing a power surge
through the entire main drive system.
那是谁?
Who was that?
- Who?
- 站住
- 谁?
- 戴帽子的
- 呃 我的一个朋友
The guy in the hat.
- Uh, a-a friend of mine.
- 他在说些什么啊？
- 是南斯拉夫语
Well, what language was he speaking?
- Yugoslavian.
你把外国人带到实验室
You let a foreigner into the lab.
- He's not a foreigner. He's my wife's
他不是外国人, 他是我老婆的叔叔亚纳什,来自南斯拉夫
Uncle Yanosh from Yugoslavia.
他是亲戚 他只是想看看实验室
He's family, and he just wanted to see
the lab, and I... and I brought him here.
我就把他带来了
他可是个天才
没看见他头那么大吗？
The man's a genius.
Did you see the size of his head?
智商高达225 超大头盖骨
225, the IQ on that man.
An extended brainpan.
- 超大头盖骨?
- 要尿尿
Extended brainpan?
Bafroom.
- No bathroom right now, Adam.
- 他刚才说"尿尿"?
- 是Bafoom，南斯拉夫语
Did he say 'bathroom'?
- Bafoon. Bafoon. Yugoslavian.
是感谢的意思
It's a term of, uh, of appreciation.
“Bafoom:谢谢你星期六带我
'Bafoon: Thank you for bringing me down
here on a Saturday to the lab...
到这实验室来参观”就这个意思
...to look around,' that's all.
用备用电机启动系统需要多长时间?
How long before we can restore
the system from the backups?
这不关你的事，你被开除出这个项目了
Well, that doesn't concern you.
You're off the project.
你无权作此决定
You don't have the authority
to make that decision.
好吧, 也许不能，那你何不直接打电话给克利福德·斯特林
Well, maybe I don't.
向他申述
So why don't you call Clifford Sterling
personally and plead your case.
但是 得知这次你给实验室造成了
However, after this morning's little
escapade, and the time and money...
时间和金钱上的损失以后
...it'll cost Sterling Labs...
我不认为老家伙还会同情你
I don't think the old man
will have a great deal of sympathy.
我想你还是不要自找没趣了
So I hope you'll spare yourself
the embarrassment of having...
省的我叫警卫...
送你出去
...to be escorted to the gate.
开始数据恢复工作
Start working data restoration backwards
from 8:56 this morning...
恢复今早8点56分后到系统崩溃的那段时间的数据
...to the exact time the system crashed.
我要知道他到底都做了些什么
I want to know what he was up to.
你为什么不告诉他们 爸爸？
Why didn't you tell 'em, Dad?
I mean, at least then...
我的意思是,至少让他们知道
他们办不到的事情你办到了
...they'd know that you were able to
make it work when nobody else could.
听着，尼克！还记得我跟你们唠叨了两天
Look, Nick. Remember we made you kids
promise never, ever to tell anyone...
让你们永远不要将你们被缩小的事告诉任何人吗？
...you were accidentally shrunk
and lost for two days?
记得
Yeah.
那是因为我不想让你们变成研究对象
That's because we didn't want
you guys to become specimens,
接受数不清的实验和无休止的观察
to undergo countless tests...
天知道还有什么
...to go through endless observations
and who knows what else.
亚当怎么办?
我们该怎么做?
What about Adam?
What are we going to do?
我不知道
I don't know.
What I do know is...
我知道的就是
我们得在你妈妈回来之前搞定一切
...we got to figure some way to fix this
before your mother gets home.
嘿 我回来了
Hi, guys.
I'm home.
这东西哪来的?
Where'd this come from?
我们该怎么办?
What do we do?
- I don't know.
我不知道
我们要不逃到墨西哥躲起来
We could drive to Mexico,
Dad, and hide out.
等他长大了再回来 我意思是岁数大了
Come back when he's bigger.
I mean, older.
- 可能她就不会注意了
- 不行
Maybe she wouldn't notice then.
- No.
最好的办法就是诚实 尼克
Honesty's the best policy, Nick.
我来向她解释
I'll just explain.
好吧
Sure. It's not the first time
something like this has happened...
反正这种事在咱们家发生...
也不是第一次了
...to our family.
我会告诉她真相
I'll just tell the truth.
- Then beg for mercy.
- 再求她原谅
- 彩色车车
Coloured car.
- 你搞什么鬼?
- 嗯...
What was that all about?
- Um, I had a little trouble...
嗯 车出了点毛病
...with the van.
我想按停车的 结果按了倒车钮
L-I-I thought I put it in, uh, in-in
park, and it went into reverse...
因为"P" 和"R" 看起来差不多...
你这么早就回来了
'cause the 'P' and the...
and the 'R' look...
来吧，大家伙
You're back early.
- Yeah, I-I took a cab from the airport.
是的，我从机场打车回来的，知道吗,我真的是很傻
You know, it really was silly.
艾米根本不需要我
Amy didn't need me at all.
Who's the man in the loud sport coat?
那个穿运动服的人是谁？
别动 不 不 那些是尼克的
Stop. No. No, those are Nick's.
好吧 黛安 我正要和你谈这事呢
Well, Diane, that's what I wanted
to talk to you about. Now, the-the...
- 坐下，坐下!
- 妈妈
Sit down.
- Mom.
你知道有时我发明的东西
You know how sometimes
the-the things that I invent...
并不完全和我设想的一致?
...don't always work
the way they're supposed to?
亲爱的 告诉我吧
Sweetheart, you can tell me.
How bad can it be?
到底
还能有多糟？
After all, it's not like you did
something to one of the kids again.
只要不再像上次那样把孩子变小
- 韦恩，亚当在哪?
- 呃
Wayne, where is Adam?
- Well, uh...
车上那个人是谁？
Who is that man in the van?
And where did this bunny come from?
这个兔子是哪来的？
- 好吧，我坦白，我闯祸了
- 闯什么祸?
All right, I confess. I did it.
- Did what?
我在这儿
Peekaboo.
我把孩子放大了
I blew up the baby.
妈妈摔倒了
Mama fall down.
Mama?
妈妈?
- 她怎么样?
- 和以前一样
How'd she take it?
- About like usual.
妈妈睡着了？
Mama sleeping?
我要杀了韦恩
I'll kill Wayne.
- You don't want to kill Wayne.
你不想杀韦恩
我要杀了韦恩
I want to kill Wayne.
他在干嘛?
What's he doing?
- He's playing with his toys.
他在玩他的玩具
快让他住手
Well, make him stop.
"让他住手"
'Make him stop.'
我怎么早没想到?
Why didn't I think of that?
亚当
Adam.
亚当 别闹了!
Adam, stop fooling around.
- 接着
- 亚当
Catch.
- Adam.
- 那是个真的火箭
- 我们出去走走 亚当
That was a real rocket.
- Let's go for a walk, Adam.
- 玩球 尼克
- 别拿东西扔尼克!
Play ball, Nick.
- Don't throw things at Nick.
接着,玩球
Catch it.
- This is your last warning.
这是你的最后警告
好吧 我再给你一次机会
Okay, I'll give you one more warning.
亲爱的，嘘，嘘，看上去也没那么糟
Honey, shh, shh.
It's not as bad as it seems.
几乎是不可能的 对吗？
It almost couldn't be,
could it?
好了, 我终于把他弄进房间了
Well, I finally got him in his room.
告诉他呆在屋里把门关上
Tell him to stay inside,
and close the door.
我已经关上了
I did close the door.
他刚刚打开了
He just opened his door.
- 他决定和我们分享
- 我把它拆了
And he decided to share it with us.
- I break off.
哦 宝贝
Oh, baby.
亚当 把门放下 亲爱的
Adam, put the door down,
sweetheart.
把门给爸爸好吗 亚当?
Why don't you give
the door to Daddy, Adam?
- 把门给爸爸 亚当
- 我来修 我来修
Give Daddy the door, Adam.
- I fix it, I fix it.
要让社区居民委员会看看
Wait till the Vista Del Mar
Standards Committee sees this.
别小题大作了 只是个信箱而已
Maybe we shouldn't bother with it.
It's just a mailbox.
小事情有时候也会出大问题 帕蒂
Little things have a way of
becoming very big things, Patty.
- 放开门 亚当
- 不 是我的门
Let go of the door, Adam.
- No, my door.
- 别伤着人
- 都住手!
Stop before someone gets hurt.
- Let go.
我来修!
I fix it.
别修了！亚当，把妈妈的咖啡桌放下
Don't fix it, Adam.
Just put down Mommy's coffee table.
- 小心 宝贝
- 慢点 亚当
Be careful, baby.
- Slow down, Adam. Ad-Ad-Adam.
噢
- 轻点 轻点
- 别动我的古董椅子!
Not my antique chair.
- Gentle. Gentle.
他们在装修吗?
回来，回这来
They remodelling in there?
- Come back. Come back here.
亚当 亚当!
Adam. Adam.
亚当 坐下
Adam, sit down. Sit down, Adam.
- He's on this side.
- 他到这边来了
- 拦住他, 爸！他在你那
- 哦 亚当
- 这不是玩游戏
He's yours.
- Oh, Adam.
This is not a game.
我们抓到他该怎么办?
What do we do when we catch him?
- Adam, Adam, hang on.
亚当，撑住
好的 等等 你们去那边 我走这边
Okay, wait. Okay.
You guys go that way. I'll go this way.
嘿 小家伙
Hi, little guy.
亚当 放下爸爸!
Adam, put Daddy down.
- 吉他
- 别进我的房间!
Guitar.
- Not my room.
亚当 放下我的吉他
放下
Adam. Adam, put down my guitar.
Put it down.
回这来，回来
Get back here.
- Come on.
他不是婴儿，他是个怪物
He's not a baby.
He's a monster.
他会弄坏我的吉他!
He's gonna break my guitar.
回来，亚当
把吉他还给我!
Come back here. Come back here.
- Come back, Adam.
Give me back my guitar.
还给我，小捣蛋！
Give it back, you brat.
另一边
Other way.
- 吉他没有了
- 拿到了 拿去 藏起来
Guitar all gone.
- Got it. Here, hide it.
他对准了什么东西
He targeted something.
But it's gonna take a lot more enhancing...
但是还要更多放大才能看清楚
你猜这里是什么?
What do you suppose this is here?
- Condensation on the lens?
- 镜头的水蒸气？
- 不是，更像固体
No, no, it's much too solid.
- How can you be sure?
- 你怎么能确定?
- 我肯定它不是水蒸气
是一团东西 我能看出来
I'm sure. It's not amorphous.
It's a mass. I can see.
到这来跟爸爸玩
Play in here with Daddy.
- 玩什么?
- 玩什么都行
Play what?
- Play anything.
- 这能让他分心
- 好极了!
This should distract him.
- Great.
That's what it's all about
You put your right foot in
You put your right foot out
and you shake it all about...
You do the Hokey Pokey
and you turn yourself around
跳舞 亚当
Yeah.
Dance, Adam.
- That's what it's all about...
很好，这只脚，亚当
Good. This foot, Adam.
- You do the Hokey Pokey...
很有趣吧  韦恩?
Isn't this fun, Wayne?
- That's what it's all about
亚当，来拍拍手，拍拍手
Clap your hands. Clap your hands.
You put your left foot in
- Put your left foot in. Good boy, Adam.
把脚放进来
You put your left foot out...
You put your left foot in
and you shake it all about
为什么关上百叶窗?
Why are you closing the shutters?
让邻居看见有个七尺高的巨型宝宝
So one of the neighbours doesn't
look in, see a seven-foot baby...
他们肯定要去通知“世界之最”不可
...and call the National Inquirer.
- 门铃
- 是谁?
That's what it's all about
- Doorbell.
Who's that?
一个邻居
One of the neighbours.
- So far, your plan's working perfectly.
现在来看 你这招还能管用
嗨！
Hi.
- Hello.
你好，我们听见喊叫声和嘈杂声
Hello.
We heard shouting and a lot of noise...
所以想来看看是不是一切正常
...so we were just wondering
if everything was all right.
哦，是的，一切都好
Oh, yes, everything's fine.
We were just entertaining.
我们只是在玩闹
亚纳什叔叔
Uncle Yanosh.
- Uncle Yanersh.
亚纳什叔叔
You put your whole self in
You put your whole self out
别太用力，地板都踩裂了
Not too hard.
You're denting the floor.
- 再见
- 爸爸 帮帮我 他抱住我了
Bye.
- Dad, help me. He's got me.
我的肋骨要断了
He's breaking my ribs.
Oh, don't do that, Adam.
别这样，亚当
天哪，好像有三只眼睛
My God, it appears to have three eyes.
是一种新生物物种
A new life-form of some sort?
放大窗口比例
Try scaling up the window.
是个大发现
可能非常大
This could be big.
- This could be very big.
好吧，我认为你干的很好
Well, I think you did a great job with
these. This should really distract him.
那样很能分散他的注意力
- 是啊 他喜欢噪音
- 给你 宝贝
Well, he likes noise.
- Here you go, honey.
好
Yeah. You know what, Nicky?
I don't care what you say.
你知道吗，尼克?无论你怎么说
这还是个围栏，亚当他不喜欢被关在围栏里
It's still a playpen,
and a playpen's a playpen to Adam.
是的，但你得承认，妈妈
Yeah, but you have to admit, Mom,
not many guys could come up with...
这没有多少人能在半小时内完成这工作
...something like this in half an hour.
- 布谷
- 不，不，亚当
Cuckoo.
- No. No. Adam.
亲爱的,离那钟远点
Sweetheart, no, no, no.
Stay away from that, sweetheart.
亚当 拜托 别碰那东西
Adam, please,
please don't touch that.
亚当，不要，别碰妈妈的布谷钟
Adam, no, don't touch Mommy's cuckoo.
过来这里 亚当
Come on away from there, Adam.
Come over here and play with Nicky.
来这里,来和尼克玩
和尼克玩，亚当
Play with Nicky, Adam.
等你有时间 帮我看看这个
When you get a minute,
you might take a look at this.
韦恩?
Wayne?
好吧...有些数据表明，在原子的内部...
Well, some of the numbers indicate
that on an atomic...
好了，宝贝，说实话，好吗？
Please, honey, the truth, okay?
- The truth, Diane, is that...
说实话，黛安, 没有那些数据,
...without the access to the data
at the plant, I don't know...
我不知道我能做些什么
...that there's anything I can do.
我只知道发生了什么 但我不知道为什么
I know what's happening,
but I don't know why.
对不起 亲爱的
I'm sorry, honey.
- Hey, Mom, look.
嘿！妈妈，看啊，我终于找到让他安静下来的方法了
I finally found a way to keep him quiet.
这里面有12支雪糕
There were 12 ice cream bars in there.
这下他可吃不下晚饭了
Well, he's ruined his dinner.
- Not necessarily, Mom.
恐怕不会，妈
看他的体重，他新陈代谢会很快的
At his body weight,
he should be able to metabolize...
也许我该闭嘴
Maybe I should just shut up about it.
好了，男孩们，我们出发吧
Okay, boys, we're going out.
- 黛安  你要干什么?
- 我要带他去实验室
Diane, what are you doing?
- I'm taking him to the lab.
也许那边有人能够...
Maybe there's somebody there who...
有人知道他们在干吗?
Who knows what they're doing?
我不是那个意思
I didn't mean it like that. I'm sorry,
but all I care about right now...
我很抱歉,但我现在所关心的
就是让宝宝缩小并恢复原状
...is getting my baby
to shrink back to normal size.
快点, 尼克，帮我把他弄上车
Come on, Nicky.
Help me get him out to the van.
缩小?黛安，等等，我有主意了
Shrink?
Diane, wait. I got an idea.
My original machine...
我原来那部机器在实验室的仓库里
...it's in the lab security warehouse.
太好了
Yes.
我们这次是秘密行动
This'll have to be a covert operation.
黛安，你跟我走，尼克，你留下看着宝宝
Diane, you come with me.
Nick, you stay with the baby.
哦 不 我们不能把他们单独留在这儿
Oh, no.
We are not leaving them here alone.
黛安 不能把他带去实验室
Diane, you can't take him to the lab.
天知道亨得利克森会怎么对待他
There's no telling what Hendrickson
will do if he gets his hands on him.
看看他,他已经很累了
Look at him.
我们出去这段时间他能睡个午觉
He's exhausted.
He can take a nap while we're gone.
不要午觉!
No nap.
看我拿的什么
Look who I got: Really Big Bunny.
好大的兔子
嗨 亚当
Hi, Adam.
Hello, Adam.
你好 亚当
你很累了是不是 亚当?
You're real tired,
aren't you, Adam?
是的 他看起来真的很累
Yeah, he looks real tired to me.
我们唱歌好吗?
Should we sing the song?
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Twinkle, twinkle, little star
♪满天都是小星星
How I wonder what you are
♪挂在天空放光明
Up above the world so high
♪就像千万小眼睛
Like a diamond in the sky
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Twinkle, twinkle, little star...
- ♪满天都是...
- 这是我的!
How I won...
- Mine.
- 放手!
- 给我!
Let go.
- Gimme.
亚当·沙兰斯基 立刻放开那只兔子!
Adam Szalinski, you let go
把爸爸放开，亚当
Put Daddy down, Adam.
It's not nice to hurt Daddy.
不可以这样对爸爸
对不起 妈妈
Sorry, Mama.
好 我来做结构分析
Okay, I'm bringing up
the structural overlay.
亨得利克森博士，我们能辨认出头发，骨头，还有金属
Dr Hendrickson, we can make out hair,
bone and metal, all sort of intertwined.
各种交织在一起
我想你应该看看这个，是的，先生
I think you should take
a look at this. Yes, sir.
他马上过来
He's on his way.
- We'll show him...
我们先让他看看角蛋白分析
...the keratin analysis first.
- 先分析重叠图像
- 还不够清晰
Structural overlay first.
- It's not clear enough.
- 我想足够了
- 为什么不问问他?
I think it is.
- Why don't we see what he thinks?
别担心 我们一小时内回来 快点
Don't worry.
We'll be back in an hour. Come on.
- 来吧
- 再见
Bye-bye.
这是我们最新的图像
This is our latest image, superimposing
structural and keratin analysis.
我们已经做了图像重叠和角蛋白分析
- 正如你看到的 它像是
- 好吧 过去点
And as you can see, there appears to...
- All right. Just move over.
是个孩子和绒毛玩具
It's a baby and a stuffed bunny.
沙兰斯基
Szalinski.
看来我得去拜访他一下
I'm gonna pay him a little visit.
继续工作
Back to work.
- I knew it was a baby.
我就知道这是个孩子
只是不确定这是只兔子
I just wasn't sure it was a bunny.
这需要点时间
This'll just take a second. They stored
all my stuff in one large crate.
他们把我所有的东西都放在一个大箱子里
- 应该很容易找到
- 哦 韦恩
It should be easy to spot.
- Oh, Wayne?
或许是按字母顺序或是别的
Maybe it's in
alphabetical order or something.
要不是怎么办?
What if it's not?
我本来是想带尼克去看电影
All I wanted to do was
take Nick to the movies. Uh-oh.
什么声音?
What?
是门铃响
Doorbell.
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶...
Twinkle, twinkle lit...
兔子
等一下
Bunny.
- Wait here.
- 曼蒂
- 里克
Mandy.
- Rick.
是尼克，尼克·沙兰斯基
Nick. Nick Szalinski.
- Right.
好吧，我是来看孩子的
我们不需要保姆了
I'm here to baby-sit.
- We don't need a baby-sitter.
亚当，不要!
Adam, no.
别逗了，我现在能进来了吗?
我已经开始收费了
Very funny. Now can I come in?
I'm already charging you.
我们改变主意了，就这样！我们不需要保姆了
We changed our mind, that's all.
We don't need a baby-sitter.
我可不这么想
I don't think so. Look, I was promised
three hours at $2.50 an hour.
听着，说好来3小时，每小时2块5的
额外工作另外加钱
Plus the extra if I'm grossed out.
- Uh, listen, Mandy.
听着，曼蒂,记住我说的，你不想看孩子
Take it from me. You don't want
to baby-sit. Not this baby.
尤其是这个孩子
我相信多怪的孩子我都能对付
I'm really sure I can
handle some stupid baby.
韦恩 我们得回去了
Wayne, we've gotta get back to the kids.
This is just taking too long.
出来的太久了
亲爱的 在那上面!
Honey, it's up here.
看看能不能找辆升降机
See if you can find a forklift.
曼蒂，相信我，一切都在我掌握中
Mandy, believe me,
I have everything under control.
如果你答应不尖叫
Now, if you promise not to scream,
I'll take the gag out of your mouth.
我就帮你解开
你保证?
Promise?
- 救命! 来人啊!
- 曼蒂! 别嚷
Help me. Someone help me.
- Mandy. Mandy, no.
求你 救命啊! 巨人宝宝!
Please, somebody help me. Giant baby.
- 你吓着他了
- 求你，放我走
You're scaring him.
Stop.
- 曼蒂，冷静点
- 救命!
Mandy, stop. Calm down.
- Help me.
什么声音?
What's that?
救命!救命!救命! 救命!
巨人宝宝！
Help. Help. Help. Help.
Giant baby. Help.
- 救命!有个巨人宝宝！
- 又是沙兰斯基家
The Slitzitskis.
- Giant baby.
韦恩这是太阳能车，我们在室内
Wayne, this is a solar van.
We're inside.
那有个开关，上面标着电池
There's a switch, honey, marked
'batteries.'Just be careful...
小心别开到
- 哦
- 高档上
...not to switch it to...
...high.
不！不
No. No.
抓紧!
Hold on.
我们再试一次?
Can we try again?
很好
Good.
Now, despite what he looks like...
别管他样子如何,
亚当只是一个婴儿
Adam is just a little kid.
他只是在那看电视 不会伤到任何人
He's-He's in there watching TV,
not hurting anyone.
♪在夏天，有个活跃的女人
Summertime.
The active woman.
♪她知道，什么是令人头痛的事
She knows what it is to have a headache.
Everybody's doin' a
brand new dance now...
♪让我们来欢迎他们
Come on, baby, do the locomotion.
- Let's welcome 'em.
♪又一次!
I know you'll get to like it
if you give it a chance now
♪扭起来！
Come on baby Do the locomotion
对不起
Sorry.
...learn than your ABCs
So come on, come on and do
the locomotion with me
那么，两年前，你爸把你和你姐姐缩小了，是吗？
So, two years ago, he made
you and your sister tiny.
还有邻居家的孩子
And the guys next door.
- Then he made you regular size again.
后来又把你们变回了原样
现在又把你弟弟变大
And now he's made your baby brother big.
是的
Right.
你没觉得这不正常吗
And you don't, like, think that's unusual.
哦！天哪，他跑出去了，而且变更大了
Oh, my God.
He's out and he's bigger.
- 你得帮我好吗?
- 工作手册里可没说有这个
You got to help me, okay?
- This wasn't in the job description.
- 我们付你加班费
- 好吧
We'll pay you overtime.
- Okay.
我可没办法给他换尿布
There's no way I'm changing those diapers.
快点
Come on.
亚当! 亚当!
Adam. Adam.
- Adam. Adam.
亚当 你在哪?
Adam, where are you?
Come on.
来吧!
朱丽娅，安静的坐下
Julia, be quiet and sit down.
现在表演著名的中国方块魔术
Now, for the famous Chinese blocks trick.
变
Shazam.
好的
Okay.
Now for my next trick.
我的下个魔术
亚当!
Adam.
现在表演失踪的兔子魔术
Now for the disappearing bunny trick.
看仔细了，我的手要比你们的眼睛快多了
Watch carefully.
The hand is quicker than the eye.
变
Shazam. Can anyone tell me
where the bunny is?
有没有人告诉我兔子到哪去了?
- 在那儿!
- 你们以为它还在我的帽子里?
There.
- You think it's still on my head?
大兔子
Big Bunny.
再见
Bye.
他在那 快点
There he is. Come on.
- I don't care if Clifford's...
我不管克利福德这个周末是不是在研究中心
我要马上向他报告
...at the Rand Institute this weekend.
我还要通知所有的董事
嘿 怎么回事
I also want the board of directors
in on this. Hey, what the...
赶快联系联邦治安官，叫他们赶过来
Contact the federal marshals.
Get 'em out here. I want something...
我还要一个足够大的东西来装...
...large enough to hold...
来装一个巨大的家伙
...to hold something large.
大兔子
大、大、大兔子
Big Bunny.
Big, Big, Big bunny.
大麻烦
In big trouble.
等等，你们待在这别动
Wait. You hold it right there.
- Hey.
我只是个保姆
I'm just the baby-sitter.
最多一小时，当然
Yeah, an hour tops. Sure.
- 韦恩，准备的怎么样了?
- 快完成了，亲爱的
Wayne, how's it coming?
- Just about got it, honey.
坐稳了 我要抄近路了
Hold on. I'm taking a short cut.
哇
我该怎么办?
What do I do?
好了，看看是不是能用
Okay, let's see if this thing works.
韦恩·沙兰斯基 马上把警察变回来
Wayne Szalinski, you unshrink
those policemen right now.
起作用了!
It works.
他们逃跑了
They're getting away.
- I think they're out...
我想他们已经出了咱们的管辖区了
...of our jurisdiction.
停下 你们不能过去
Hold it.
You can't go in.
没事，警官，那是我家
It's okay, Officer.
That's our house.
让一下
Excuse me.
我的孩子在哪? 他们在哪?
Where are my boys? Where are they?
- Hold on, folks. Hold it.
等一下，两位，等一下
Hold it just a minute.
我是普莱斯顿·布鲁克斯，联邦探员
Preston Brooks, US Marshals.
Now, we found this guy down the street...
我们发现这个家伙藏在车库后面
...hiding in a garage.
孩子们很安全,沙兰斯基太太
The children are perfectly safe,
Mrs Szalinski. We just needed...
我们只是想多给婴儿一点空间
免得他伤着自己
...to get the baby some more room
当然 我们要马上把变异的孩子带回去检查
Of course, the mutated child
will have to undergo immediate testing.
你说的是我的孩子
That's my kid you're talking about.
Let go of me.
放开我!
- 等一下 沙兰斯基先生
- 放开我
Hold on, Mr Szalinski.
- Let go of me.
你们不能把他关在卡车里
You can't keep him in that truck.
别担心,我都安排好了
Don't worry.
It's all fixed up.
对你弟弟来说 这只是个大围栏
As far as your brother's concerned,
it's one big playpen.
- 这正是我担心的
- 如果我是你我就听他的
That's what I mean.
- I'd listen to him if I were you.
听着 小姐 需要你意见的时候我会问你
Look, Miss. When I want your opinion,
I'll ask for it.
妈妈,救我
Mama, help.
出去! 出去!
Out. Out.
他脖子有40英寸
He's got a 40-inch neck.
亚当会没事的,夸克，我知道
Adam's going to be fine, Quark.
- The parents are here.
孩子的父母在这
等孩子安全到达后我会带他们去见面
We'll bring them to meet
the child when he's secure.
我可以批准的
I can authorize that.
- Marshal Brooks?
布鲁克斯警官?
我坚决要求您逮捕这两个人
I'm afraid I have to insist
that these two be taken into custody.
- 什么罪名?
- 盗窃 故意损坏他人财物
On what charge?
- Theft. Malicious mischief.
还有危害儿童
Child endangerment.
失陪了
If you'll excuse me.
克利福德先生
Clifford.
Well, I hardly know what to say.
好吧。我能不知道该怎么说
我从一开始就提醒你要提防着沙兰斯基
I tried to warn you about Szalinski
from the very beginning.
对 你说过 查尔斯
Yes. Yes, you did, Charles.
说点安慰你的话
If it's any consolation to you,
the board of directors believed...
董事会一直相信你是对的
...that you were right all along.
斯特林博士！斯特林博士！
我能把儿子恢复原样
Dr Sterling. Dr Sterling, sir.
I can reverse my son's growth.
给我一次机会，先生！我能让他恢复正常
Just give me a chance, sir.
- 你能?
- 用什么 沙兰斯基?
You can?
- Yeah, with what, Szalinski?
用可口可乐瓶?
Coca-Cola bottles?
哼? 也许是口香糖或是绳子？
Hmm? Maybe some, what,
chewing gum and twine?
你以为你是谁 敢这样跟他说话？
Just who do you think you are,
talking to him like that?
黛安 让我来处理
Diane, let me handle this.
你以为你是谁 敢这样跟他说话？
Who do you think you are,
talking to me like that?
克利福德先生,现在的情况必须要我
Clifford...
...the situation demands
that I bring in the people...
找些专家和有资格的人
...with the expertise and the credentials.
等等 你认为我只是一个满脑子疯狂主意
Wait a second. You think I'm just
some guy from Fresno...
躲在阁楼的乡巴佬吗？
...who tinkered with crackpot
ideas in his attic?
好吧，让我告诉你
Well, let me tell you something.
整个国家的基础都是建立在
This whole country is built on
the shoulders of people who tinkered...
那些满脑子疯狂主意的
躲在阁楼、地下室和后院的乡巴佬的肩上
...with crackpot ideas in attics
and basements and backyards.
亚历山大·格林汉姆·贝尔在只有两个房间的公寓里工作
Alexander Graham Bell
working in a two-room flat.
年轻人 想说服我
Young man, don't presume...
别站在那儿用那些伟大的理想和伟大的发明家
...to stand there and lecture me
about great minds...
来给我上课
...and great inventors.
无论这些年我做了什么 我从来都不是傻瓜...
Whatever I've been over the years,
I've never been a fool...
也从不和傻瓜搅在一起
...or been involved with anyone else who is.
我现在当然也不想破例
I certainly don't intend to start now.
- 查尔斯?
- 是的，克利福德先生?
Charles?
- Yes, Clifford?
- 你被解雇了
- 什么？
You're fired.
你被解雇了
What?
- You're fired.
那么，沙兰斯基 你打算怎么做
So Szalinski, what have you got in mind,
so we can get that kid of yours...
才能在睡觉前让你的孩子恢复正常？
...back to normal size by bedtime?
先生 设备原型在我车上...
Well, sir, the prototype's in the van...
- Hold on, folks. We've got a problem.
等等,先生们,我们有麻烦了
你儿子跑了 他现在有50英尺高
Your son's escaped,
and he's over 50 feet tall.
不可能！我儿子才14英尺高
That's impossible.
My son's only 14 feet tall.
- 我来开车
- 那也很高了
I'll drive.
- That's still pretty tall.
给我接泰伦斯·惠勒
Yes, get me Terence Wheeler.
This is an emergency.
有急事
他逃跑了?
他挣脱了，还把卡车翻了个底朝天
He broke out?
- He busted out of the truck...
...and knocked it completely over.
那他现在在干吗?
What's he doing now?
- He's just standing there.
他就站在那儿，还在微笑
But he's smiling.
亚当 坐下
Now, Adam, sit down.
- Nick, I don't think sitting's...
尼克，我不认为坐下是个好主意
...such a good idea.
噢，玩具
Ooh, toys.
他干了什么?
He did what?
- Put your son and the baby-sitter...
把你儿子和保姆放进口袋里走了
...in his pocket and left.
他老是这样
He's always doing that. I find
the strangest things in his pockets.
我在他口袋里总能发现奇怪的东西
韦恩 你认为是什么导致这种生长现象?
Wayne, what do you suppose
is causing this growth phenomenon?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们沿着铜矿公路运送他
They were transporting him
along Copper Mine Road.
沿路两边都是高压电线
That runs alongside high-voltage lines.
- Oh.
哦?
昨天我给他做午餐时 他坐在微波炉前
And yesterday when I gave him lunch,
he was right near the microwave oven.
你还说过他在看电视突然变大
And you said the baby grew
while he was watching TV.
- 当然!
- 我不明白你们在说什么
Of course.
I don't understand any of this.
- Electromagnetic flux.
电流磁场
所有使用中的电器周围
Around every operating
electrical device, there's a flux.
都有磁流
就像一个电磁力场
Like an electromagnetic force field.
- That's what's causing the baby to grow.
这正是造成婴儿猛长的原因
那这个电磁...
Would this electromagnetic, uh...
Would it surround neon lights too?
霓虹灯附近也有电磁场吗？
对, 怎么?
Yeah, why?
- Your kid. He's headed toward Las Vegas.
你儿子，他正朝拉斯维加斯走去
噢，不
Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh.
你没有被解雇，绝对没有
You are not fired,
not by a long shot.
这正是我期待已久的机会
This is the opportunity
I've been waiting for. At last.
斯特林终于做的太过分了
Sterling has gone too far this time.
今晚会开董事会
The board is getting together tonight.
Until then, I want you on this.
在那之前，我要你继续这事
无论如何 都要把局面给我控制住
Whatever it takes, just get
the situation under control.
好的，我有一个想法，先生
但我需要军方配合
Yeah, I did have one thought, sir,
but I'll need military cooperation.
好的，我来想办法
Fine. I'll get the clearance. Charles,
Just-Just-Just handle this for us.
查尔斯,不过...
你一定要为我们处理好这事
我们... 我们做的才是对的
We'll... We'll do the right thing by you.
据警方通报，有一个巨型生物
Police reports just in say that
some kind of large creature...
逃离了政府管制
正向市中心方向移动
...has just escaped from a government
caravan and is heading toward the city.
沙兰斯基太太 如果他朝亮光走
Mrs Szalinski, if he heads for
the lights, he has to come this way.
一定会走这条路
据我的计算
According to my calculations,
he's gotta hold still for 12.2 seconds.
他会保持12.2秒静止不动
怎么?
What?
他长大了 需要增加照射时间
His increased mass requires
a longer period of exposure.
你怎么能指望一个2岁大的孩子
How do you expect
to get a two-year-old to hold...
会保持12秒一动不动?
...still for 12 point anything seconds?
她说的对 博士
She's right, Doctor,
we tried to have his picture...
上个月我们想给他照张相，都没成功
...taken a month ago. Total bust.
我们正在接近现场，丹
We're just pulling up now, Dan.
There are a lot of police cars gathered.
这里聚集了很多警车
我去问问情况
马上叫医护人员!
We'll find out what's going on.
- Call the paramedics now.
好了，就在这拍摄
All right, here's a shot.
Okay.
我是康斯坦丝·温特斯 在现场向您报道
This is Constance Winters
reporting live from the site...
这肯定会成为
...of what will certainly become the
most important news story of the decade.
这10年以来最重大的新闻
丹，我看见一个巨人...
Dan, I'm seeing a giant.
哦 我的天哪
Oh, my God.
哦 亚当
Oh, Adam.
亲爱的 他看起来不错
Well, honey, he looks okay.
- Let me see.
让我来看看
你觉得这会影响他的人生吗？
Do you think this is gonna
affect him for life? I mean,
我想这种事会毁了这孩子
something like this could ruin a kid.
亲爱的，我想这能帮他从不同的角度
Honey, it might give him
a different perspective,
来审视人生
help him see the big picture.
宝贝，他们在那儿
Baby.
There they are.
- 大家就位
- 我和你一起，伙计
Let's move into position.
- I'm with you, pal.
- 救命!
- 把我们从这弄下来!
Help.
- Get us down from here.
- 弄下来!
- 我们在上面!
Get us down.
We're up here.
- We're up in the pocket.
我们在口袋里!
This is Constance Winters...
...在向你实况直播，刚查明这个巨大宝宝名字叫
...reporting live
on the progress of the giant baby...
亚当·沙兰斯基 来自滨海社区
...who has just been identified...
...as Adam Szalinski from Vista Del Mar.
州长来电话找您 先生
Let's go.
- The governor's on the phone...
他只是个很大的婴儿
我们可以用绳索枪 用绳子捆住他
I can get rope guns.
We can shoot ropes over him.
绝对不行！不许向我的宝宝射任何东西
Absolutely not. You are not
shooting anything at my baby.
宝宝? 看看他
Baby? Look at him.
- Hey, we're his parents, okay?
嘿 我们是他父母！我们会处理这事
We'll handle this.
- 黛安?
- 什么事 韦恩?
Diane?
- Yeah, Wayne?
咱们怎么办?
How do we handle this?
准备!
注意！当心!
Ready.
- Watch out. Look out. Look out.
妈妈
Mommy. Mom.
妈!
- 尼克，你没事吧?
- 亚当，把你哥哥放下来
Nicky, are you okay?
- Adam, put your brother down.
亚当，宝贝，妈妈在这
Adam, baby, Mommy's here.
- Nicky, I'm gonna get you...
尼克，我现在就把你弄下来!
...out of here right away.
好的，爸爸，快点！
Okay, Dad, but hurry.
我们可以找辆消防车过来，用云梯上去救他们
We can get a fire truck in here
and run a ladder up to 'em.
云梯还到不了他的膝盖
That ladder wouldn't even
reach beyond his knees.
亚当，现在慢慢坐下来
Adam, now sit down really slowly.
有办法了! 大兔子
I got it. Big Bunny.
I need Big Bunny.
我需要个大兔子
- 我需要一个大笨蛋？
- 不，是兔子！
I need something called Big Dummy?
- No, Bunny.
- 兔子?
- 他最爱的玩具!
Bunny?
- It's his favourite toy.
那是孩子最喜欢的玩具
It's the kid's favourite toy.
直升机正飞来了 下面吊着像是
A helicopter is approaching
with what looks like...
巨大毛绒玩具一类的
...a giant stuffed animal of
some sort hanging from it.
- 谢谢
- 亲爱的 这很危险!
Thanks.
- Honey, this is dangerous.
- 别担心
- 飞行员在等你，韦恩
Don't worry.
- Pilot's ready for you, Wayne.
已经预热好了
It's all primed. Be ready
to activate as soon as he's down.
准备好他一下来就启动
我不会有事的
I'll be fine.
我很肯定爸爸有办法救我们
I'm positive my dad will
have a plan to get us...
告诉我 这是在做梦
Tell me I'm not seeing this.
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Twinkle, twinkle little star
♪满天都是小星星
How I wonder what you are...
- 我说过我爸爸会有办法的
- ♪挂在天空放光明
Up above the world so high
- I told you my Dad would have a plan.
- ♪就像许多小眼睛
- 兔子
Like a diamond in the sky
- Bunny.
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Twinkle, twinkle little star
♪满天都是小星星
How I wonder what you are...
♪一闪，一闪，亮晶晶
Radio it in. Radio...
- Twinkle, twinkle little star
♪满天都是
How I wonder what you are
♪小星星
哦 我累了
Oh, I'm tired.
Are you tired, Big Bunny?
你累吗 大兔子？
哦 是的 我真的累了
Oh, yeah, I'm really tired.
不知道我为什么这么累
I can't remember when I was this tired.
准备！斯特林博士，他眨眼睛了
Get ready, Dr Sterling.
He's getting blinky.
是啊 我也是
Yeah, me too.
- 我不知道该做什么
- 他困了!
I don't know what to do.
- He's getting sleepy.
起作用了，你丈夫是个天才
It's working.
Your husband's a genius.
我有个主意
I got an idea.
Why don't we all have a nice...
为什么我们不一起睡个...
- 不!
- 美美的
No.
- Long...
- 别说!
- 午觉?
Don't say it.
- Nap?
- 抓紧了!
- 不要午觉!
Brace yourself.
- No nap.
哇! 救命! 坚持住!
Whoa. Help. Help. Hang on.
Get me away from him. Move me away.
把我弄走 离开这里！
不睡午觉!
No nap.
- 知道了，不睡觉!
- 坚持住，爸！
I get it. No nap.
- Hold on, Dad.
把我吊起来 或者把我放下来
Take me up or put me down.
Take me away.
罗伊, 让我们靠近点!
Roy, let's move in closer.
我要跳了！我要跳了！
I'm gonna jump. I'm gonna jump.
- Release the bunny.
放下兔子
- 哇!
- 爸!
Whoa.
- Dad.
快放!
Release it now.
快跑!
Run.
- Run.
Whoa.
- 爸爸 这是曼蒂
- 嗨
Dad, this is Mandy.
- Hi...
待在那别动 孩子
Stay right there, kids. There's
absolutely nothing to worry about.
没什么好担心的
我感觉好多了
I feel a whole lot better.
噢!
- 那是我爸爸
- 他看上去人很好
That's my dad.
- He seems really nice.
快跑，爸！ 当心他的脚
Run, Dad.
Watch out for his foot.
哇!
你没事吧？干的好 伙计
Are you all right?
Nice try, buddy.
他朝市中心走去
He's headed for the strip.
- You little devil.
小捣蛋鬼
他朝市中心走去
He's heading toward the city. We'll
follow and bring you a live update.
我们会跟着他并给您最新的直播
亚当·沙兰斯基 我是妈妈
Adam Szalinski, this is your
Mommy talking. You stop right now.
立刻给我停下来
恐怕这没什么用 沙兰斯基太太
Afraid that won't do any good,
Mrs Szalinski. I'm sure he expects...
他肯定认为妈妈应该比他更大
...his mommy to be bigger than he is.
现在在他的眼里...
To him you're just...
Well, you're nothing more...
你只是个会说话的玩具
...than a little talking doll.
现在没什么能阻止他了
Nothing can stop him now.
我不知道他们想要干嘛
I don't know what
these guys are gonna want, but...
但咱们必须合作
...we'll have to cooperate with 'em.
- 好吧 去通知大家
- 是 长官
All right, go brief the men.
- Yes, sir.
亨得利克森博士，我是内华达国民警卫队
的埃德·迈尔森上尉
Dr Hendrickson. Captain Ed Myerson,
Nevada State Militia.
上尉 希望咱们能尽快结束混乱
Captain, let's hope
we can wrap this up quickly.
正如你知道的 先生
Just so you're aware, sir.
我得到的命令是没有最终授权前我们不能随便行动
My orders state we do nothing
without final authorization.
坦白讲，上尉
Frankly, Captain, I'm not under
the jurisdiction of the state militia.
我不属于军方辖制
你的命令和我没关系
Your orders mean nothing to me.
巨人宝宝正向市中心走去
A giant infant is heading toward the city.
这宝宝有50英尺高
The baby is over 50 feet tall and
appears to be growing even bigger...
而且还在以惊人的速度长大
...at an alarming rate.
好吧，行动吧，上尉！立刻！
All right, let's move it, Captain, now.
- Lf it's okay with you,
如果你不介意 我就坐着了
I'll just sit tight.
..随事态发展将会有更多的新闻
More on this story as it develops.
我的脚好像碰到什么东西
There's something down by my foot.
看这个
Look at this.
- Wow.
哇, 看看还有什么别的
Let's see what else is down here.
麦片
Cereal. Hey cool, want some?
嘿 真棒 来点吗？
不，谢谢！我在节食
No, thanks. I'm on a diet.
来个葡萄干
Have a raisin.
为了您的安全 请离开街道
Please clear the streets for your own safety.
请待在家里，这是紧急情况
Please stay indoors.
This is an emergency.
所有行人都会有危险
All pedestrians are in grave danger.
请离开街道!
Please clear the streets.
这是紧急通知，这不是演习
This is the Emergency Broadcast System.
This is not a test.
一个巨大的人类宝宝正朝本市走来
A human baby of abnormal proportions
is approaching the city.
这巨人正以极快的速度成长
The giant appears
to be growing at a tremendous rate...
已经达到100英尺
...and has now reached 100 feet.
发生什么事了？
是韦恩·牛顿来了吗?
What's happening here?
Is Wayne Newton in town?
不，韦恩·牛顿不够格
No, they don't do this for Wayne Newton.
It must be somebody bigger.
- 一定是比他还大牌的人
- 听着，宝贝
亲爱的，在这城里没人比韦恩·牛顿更大牌了
Listen, babe, there's nobody bigger
than Wayne Newton in this town.
当然，也可能我弄错了
Of course, I could be wrong.
- Peekaboo.
我在这呢!
- 是他变大了还是我们缩小了？
- 真不可思议
Is he growing or are we shrinking?
It's amazing. He's doubled in size
in just a few minutes.
几分钟时间他又长了一倍
亚当! 放我们下来
Adam. Put us down.
You put us down now.
立刻放我们下来!
你好啊 伙计
Howdy, partners.
欢迎来到拉斯维加斯
Welcome to downtown Las Vegas.
嗨，伙计
- 你还好吗?
- 是 我没事
Are you okay?
- Yeah, I think so.
他现在向佛瑞蒙大街走去
He's toddling down the centre
of Fremont Street.
他知道不该单独上街
He knows not to go in the street by himself.
很难说他到底能长多高
There's no telling how huge he might get.
尤其是他继续走近那些灯
Especially if he touches any of those lights.
我们得让他离开那儿
We've got to get him away from them.
不可能 根本没法让他走开
But how? There's nothing
that's gonna make him leave.
除非他看到他更想要的东西
Unless he sees something
that he wants more.
叫你的人靠边，我想韦恩有主意了
Tell your men to pull over.
I think Wayne's got an idea.
拦住那辆冰淇淋车
Follow that ice-cream truck.
我需要一个很大的扩音器
We'll need a really big loudspeaker.
Who can drive an ice-cream truck...
谁能把冰淇淋车开的飞快?
我们用对讲机保持联络
We'll be with you on the walkie-talkie.
我是普莱斯顿·布鲁克斯,联邦治安官
我们现在要征用这辆车
Preston Brooks, US Marshals. We're
commandeering this vehicle. Come on.
- 上车！
- 稍等!
Hey, wait a minute.
- 这是什么?
- 一个镇静剂发射器
What's that?
- It's a tranquillizer cannon.
用来对付大型的哺乳动物
It's used on large mammals.
镇静剂能在几秒内将目标控制
Cartridges can incapacitate
a target in seconds.
就像打针一样
It's like a normal injection, but
on a slightly larger scale, of course.
当然，只是比例大了很多
老实说，先生，我自己也有小孩
Frankly, sir, I have kids myself
and that just doesn't seem...
这些看来这好像不太合乎逻辑
...like the type of...
当然了，上尉
Well, naturally, Captain.
This is just a... a last resort.
这是，这只是最后的手段
我是布雷德利·斯旺勒
正在著名的灯光峡谷做现场直播
Reporting live from the famous Glitter
Gulch where certainly the biggest story...
马上将会发生本年度最大的新闻
...of the year is unfolding.
赌场老板有些失望
Casino owners are understandably upset.
They've been ordered...
他们被迫撤离该地区...
...to evacuate the area.
目前有两个关键人物可以回答我们的许多问题
The answers to many of our questions lie
with two key players in this drama...
斯特林实验室的克利福德·斯特林博士
Dr Clifford Sterling
of Sterling Laboratories...
据我们所知，这个孩子叫
What we do know is that a baby...
亚当·沙兰斯基
...by the name of Adam Szalinski
has somehow measured over 100 feet tall.
他身高已经超过了100英尺
别鼓掌了
Stop the clapping.
我有办法了
I got a plan.
- Great.'Cause I'm...
太好了 因为我已经开始晕机了
...starting to get airsick.
我们把线从口袋底拉出来
We'll pull the thread out
of the bottom of the pocket and...
然后把它作为绳索 滑下去
...use it as a rope to slide down.
现场一片混乱
The scene here is one
of total confusion and chaos.
不过目前为止，所有赌场都还在那
But so far all the casinos are still standing.
小心!
Watch out.
嗨！
Hi.
- Hey. Hey, don't. What are you doin'?
嘿，别这样！ 你在干吗？
停车 停车
Stop. Stop. Stop.
我们快跳吧
We'll have to jump.
抓紧绳子
Hold on.
别往下看
看着点换挡器 跳！
Don't look down. Watch out
for the gearshift. Jump.
- 快开!
- 我在开!
Go.
- I'm trying.
我在开!我在开!
Truly, I'm trying.
- Stayin'alive...
- 快点 想想办法！
- 我只会开自动档的
Hurry. Hurry, do something.
- Stayin'alive
咱们得快离开这
I'm used to an automatic.
Stayin'alive
- We've gotta get out of here.
玩具车
Toy car.
系好安全带!
Buckle up.
从路上离开!
Adam, get him away from me.
- Adam.
亚当 别吃掉我们！
Adam. Adam. Don't eat us.
哇
Whoa.
我们正在灯光峡谷直播
We're here live in Glitter Gulch,
standing just below Adam Szalinski...
就站在亚当·沙兰斯基的下面
他把一辆黄色小跑车举到空中
...who has lifted a small yellow
sports car into the air...
车上有三个不明身份的人
...with three unidentified persons in it.
从我这看
From what I can make out,
it looks like two young teenagers,
其中两个像是年轻人 一男一女
a boy and a girl...
和一个穿着印第安服装的男子
...and a man dressed in an Indian costume.
他在干什么?
What's he doing?
- He's taking something out...
他在从口袋里掏东西，一颗薄荷糖
...of his pocket. A peppermint.
伙计!
哇哦! 哇哦!
Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
嘿, 伙计
Howdy, partners.
哦，天哪！
那车在他手上就像玩具
That car is like a toy to him.
希望这车有安全气囊
I hope this thing has air bags.
想想办法 尼克! 让他停下来
Do something, Nick. Tell him to stop.
- I can't. He's too big.
我没办法 他太大了
快让他离开灯
We gotta get him away from those lights
before he touches any of them.
否则会把他们弄碎的
布鲁克斯 冰淇淋车怎么样了?
Brooks, what's happening
with that ice-cream truck?
- 快好了
- 收到
We're almost set.
- Roger.
不!
No.
- Watch the tree.
小心树!
- 哦 不！我要吐了!
- 别!
Oh, no.
只是个大孩子在玩玩具
Just a big baby with his toy.
过来啦!
Coming through.
都让开!
Get out of the way.
- 听话 亚当 放下
- 把他放下 宝贝
Come on, Adam, put it down.
Put it down.
Come on, sweetheart. Put it down.
哇!
他要干什么?
What's he doing now?
把我们放下!把我们放下!
Put us down.
他放下了
He put it down.
把我们拿起来!把我们拿起来!
Pick us up.
哦 天哪 我们要死了
Oh, my God. We're gonna die. We're gonna
die. We're gonna die in a convertible.
- 车还没好吗?
- 布鲁克斯? 发生什么了?
What about that truck?
- Brooks? What's happening there?
好了
Okay. We're set.
准备好了
- 不 等等
- 停下 停下!
No. Wait.
- Hold it. Hold it.
先让他把孩子弄下来
We need him to get the kids down.
把音乐关掉!
Cut it off.
- 我受不了了
- 哦 天哪
I can't stand it.
- Oh, my God.
噢!
不管怎样 别往下看
Whatever you do,
don't look down.
- 尼克 别松手 求你了
- 我不会的
Nick, don't let go. Please.
- I won't.
我要把你拉回来 好吗？
I'm gonna pull you back up, okay?
- 尼克! 曼蒂!
- 坚持住!
Nick. Mandy.
- Hold on.
- 但你得帮手
- 好的
But you gotta help.
- Okay.
过来拿车 亚当!
Get the car, Adam.
亚当! 把车拿起来!
Adam. Pick up the car.
- 把车拿起来!
- 来啊！亚当，来
Adam, get the car.
- Come on, Adam. Come on.
过来 亲爱的
Come on, sweetheart.
来吧 我抓住你了
Come on. I got you.
车子掉了
Car fall down.
锁上车门
Lock your door.
谢谢你 亚当
Thank you, Adam.
- 他把他们放到口袋里了
- 亲爱的 我们不能再等了
He put 'em in the pocket.
- Honey, we can't wait any longer.
开始行动吧
Let's do it.
现在所有人准备
各单位注意,所有赌场,
Everyone stand by now.
Attention, all casinos, wait...
等我信号开始关灯
...for my signal to turn off your lights.
布鲁克斯警官 把车开过来
Marshal Brooks,
bring on the truck.
尼克，快点
Nick, come on.
预备，开始！联合广场关灯
Ready, set, go, Union Plaza.
金门广场关灯
Go, Golden Gate.
拉斯维加斯俱乐部关灯
Las Vegas Club.
现在 请打开探照灯
Now, hit the searchlights.
布鲁克斯，走！
Go, Brooks.
幸运女士, 头奖俱乐部关灯
Lucky Lady. Jackpot.
- 来啊,亚当！来吧,宝贝
- 快点 宝贝 去追啊
Come on, Adam.
- Come on, baby.
Come on, baby. Go for it.
灯光赌场关灯
Glitter Gulch. Golden Goose.
- 金鹅赌场关灯
- 冰淇淋
硬币城堡关灯
Ice cream.
- Coin Castle.
比尼恩马蹄铁赌场关灯
Binion's Horseshoe. Vegas World.
维加斯世界关灯
这肯定是我爸爸的另一个计划
This must be another
one of my dad's plans.
- 星宫俱乐部关灯
- 好极了
Star Palace.
- Great.
四个皇后关灯
4 Queens. The Fremont.
佛瑞蒙大街关灯
- 成功了 韦恩
- 走啊 亚当!
It's working, Wayne.
- Go, Adam.
他很喜欢冰淇淋
嗯!
He really likes ice cream.
- 是的!
- 成功了!
Yes.
- It's working.
- 冰淇淋!
- 你们在哪?
Ice cream.
- Where are you guys?
孩子快追上我了
This kid's gaining on me.
我们有命令了，上尉
起飞
We have clearance, Captain.
Move it.
布鲁克斯说他在城外抓住了冰淇淋车
Brooks said he caught the ice-cream
truck just outside of town.
然后他就把雪糕拽下了车
Next thing I know, he grabbed
it right off the truck.
- 他拿那个干吗?
- 还能干什么?
What'd he do with it?
- What do you think he did with it?
- 还有别的主意吗?
- 会有的 快点 咱们走
You got another idea?
- I will. Come on. Let's go.
- 斯特林博士
- 韦恩!
Dr Sterling?
- Wayne.
你还记得
Do you remember how we got Adam to
hold still to have his picture taken?
我们怎么给他照的相吗？
- 我把他放在两腿中间紧紧抓住他
- 是吗?
I put him in my lap and I held him.
亲爱的 他需要我
Yeah?
- Honey, he needs me.
问题是对亚当来说，他的妈妈应该比他的个子更大
The problem is, to Adam, his mommy
is somebody much bigger than he is.
不 黛安 你疯了吗？
韦恩!
No, Diane. It's a crazy idea...
- Wayne.
20年来 我看你不断的冒出各种疯狂的念头
For almost 20 years I've watched
you have one crazy idea after another.
现在轮到我有一个了
It's my turn to have just one.
噢!
火
Fire.
- 我的吉他
- 哦!
My guitar.
- Uh-oh.
- 又怎么了?
- 亚当，别碰那个吉他!
What now?
- Adam, don't touch that guitar.
我开始预热激光了，600伏
I am pre-heating the lasers now,
600 volts.
黛安 应该让我去 不是你
Diane, I should be doing this, not you.
有个道理是每个小孩子都懂的
There's one thing every little kid knows.
爸爸说的是好玩
Daddies mean fun.
Mommies mean business.
妈妈说的就是当真
可是，这个设备从没用来放大过人
But-But-But this was never meant
to do anything like this.
激光量过小，你会和亚当一样长的太慢
Too little power and you'll
grow too slowly like Adam.
- 激光量过大 你会
- 我相信你，韦恩·沙兰斯基
And too much power...
- I trust you, Wayne Szalinski.
韦恩 是时候变大了
Wayne, time to get large.
这是你要的苏打水， 先生
Here's your soda, sir.
你要可乐瓶干什么?
What do you need a Coke bottle for?
- I don't.
不是，我只要瓶底
Just the bottom.
- Oh.
哦
汤姆,我刚就在硬石咖啡厅外面
Tom, I'm here just outside the Hard Rock
Cafe. The giant baby is approaching.
那巨大宝宝正在接近
喂? 我听不清
Hello? I can't hear you.
Turn off the lights?
灯关了?
一个巨大的什么? 宝宝?
A giant what? Baby?
吉他!
Guitar.
Oh, my God.
- Let's get out of here.
为了您的安全 请留在室内
For your own safety,
please stay indoors.
离开大街！
亚当! 别碰那吉他!
Adam. Don't touch the guitar.
I'll save ya.
不要, 亚当!
亚当，放下那吉他!
No, Adam.
Adam, put down the guitar.
这玩意不能再快点了吗？
孩子可能还在长!
Can't this thing go any faster?
The kid might be growing again.
这已经是最快的速度了 博士
This is as fast as we can go safely, Doctor.
康斯坦丝·温特斯从街对面的硬石咖啡厅里
Constance Winters live across
the street from the Hard Rock Cafe.
为您做直播
他以为那吉他是个真的乐器
He thinks the guitar
is a real musical instrument.
他想用它弹个曲子
He's trying to play a tune.
再靠近点 开稳点
Bring me into range and hold it steady.
- Doctor, wait a minute.
博士 等一下
如果我们击中他 他倒下会压向人群的
Now, if we hit him and he stumbles,
he could fall into the crowd.
那我们只有求上天保佑了
Well, we'll just have to hope
that doesn't happen.
亚当，把吉他放下，去抓飞机
Adam, put down the guitar
and get the aeroplane.
飞机 你好
Aeroplane. Hi.
稳住
Hold it. Steady.
别晃
他们向亚当开枪了!
They're shooting at Adam.
- I assume that little manoeuvre...
上尉，刚刚那次就当是你的失误
...was an error, Captain.
现在稳住了 否则我肯定这是你最后一次飞行任务
Now steady, or I'll make sure this
is the last mission you ever fly.
去找个和你一样大的人较量吧
Hey. Pick on somebody your own size.
哇!
Ow.
好吧 再来一次
All right, let's go again.
丹...
Dan, the...
稳住
Hold it stead...
退后
Back off.
是，女士
Yes, ma'am.
告诉他们 那是我妈妈!
You tell 'em.
That's my mom.
我需要个休假
I need a vacation.
- Whoa. Look at that mother.
哇 看那是他妈妈
过来 宝贝
Come here, baby.
- Mama.
妈妈!
到妈妈这来
Come to Mommy.
过来，宝贝，到妈妈这来
Come here, baby.
Come to Mommy.
妈妈!
Mom. Easy, Mom.
妈妈 慢点
一切都过去了，宝贝
Everything's gonna be okay,
sweetie.
妈妈在这
Mommy's here.
- Everything it's got, Doctor.
- 所有准备就绪 博士
- 收到
Roger.
你在哭吗?
You crying?
- Yeah. It's okay to cry...
是的 当你特别高兴的时候也是可以哭的
...when you're so happy.
发电机的轴承快烧坏了
The bearings in the generator are
about to burn out. We better do it.
我们最好来吧
好的，现在看着爸爸
Okay, now, look at Daddy.
Smile for Daddy.
对爸爸笑一个
- 他在那儿
- 爸爸
There he is.
- Daddy.
韦恩 1450已经是最大极限了
Wayne, 1450.
It's all she can take.
- 笑一个，亚当
- 笑个，亚当
Say cheese, Adam.
- Cheese, Adam.
快点，韦恩
Come on, Wayne.
- 快看 亚当 爸爸在那
- 爸爸
Look, Adam, there's Daddy.
- Daddy.
亲爱的 你成功了
Honey, you did it.
亚当
Adam.
你着实把我们吓了一跳 小家伙
You gave us quite a scare, little man.
- I knew you could do it, honey.
我就知道你能做到 亲爱的
他在那儿! 让我过去
There he is.
Let me through.
好吧, 沙兰斯基，你成功了，谁能想到呢？
Well, Szalinski, you pulled it off.
Who would have thought?
亨得利克森博士
Dr Hendrickson,
that looked like some sort of rifle...
刚刚没看错的话，你好像用枪打我的孩子
...that you were shooting at my baby.
那是镇静剂
They were tranquillizer cartridges. They
wouldn't have hurt him, I assure you.
他们不会伤害他的，我保证
哦
Oh. Tranquillizer cartridges.
镇静剂
永远别惹妈妈
Never cross Mommy.
- We got an emergency here.
我们需要辆救护车，亨得利克森博士需要帮助
Dr Hendrickson needs help.
He's overcome with the prospect...
让他另谋高就，把他吓晕过去了
...of having to find a new career.
嘿 大家伙 这是你刚在找的吗？
Hey, big fella, is this
what you were lookin' for?
噢
韦恩! 尼克和曼蒂呢!
Wayne. Nick and Mandy.
他们在...
Weren't they in Adam's pocket?
- In Adam's pocket.
在亚当的口袋里!
- 别告诉我...
- 哦 天哪
Don't tell me.
- Oh, my God.
亲爱的，我把孩子缩小了
Honey, I shrunk the kids.
Nobody move.
所有人都别动
别担心
Don't worry. I have highly specialized
equipment to deal with this.
我有特殊的设备能找到他们
我需要头盔和我的狗
I'll need the helmet and I'll need the dog.
早上好，拉斯维加斯，所有车辆不准
Good morning, Las Vegas.
All vehicles are asked...
接近硬石咖啡厅，发明家韦恩·沙兰斯基
...to stay clear of the Hard Rock Cafe
where inventor Wayne Szalinski...
正在独自寻找他失踪的孩子
...is conducting a one-man search
to find some missing children.
沙兰斯基的物体放大仪器
It was Szalinski's matter-expanding
machine that was responsible...
昨晚引起了惊人的事件
...for last night's amazing events.
克利福德·斯特林博士刚刚宣布
Dr Clifford Sterling has just announced...
我猜你爸爸今天是世界上最出名的人
I guess your father's about
the most famous guy in the world today.
而你是最勇敢的人
And I guess you're about the bravest.
谢谢你救了我的命
That's for saving my life.
这算不了什么
It wasn't much.
我不是说你的生命不算什么
I don't mean your life wasn't much.
我是说，我所做的算不上什么
What I did wasn't so much.
Ours if we want it
Tonight has our initials on it
他们要多久才能找到我们呢？
How long do you think
it'll take before they find us?
我想还得过一会吧
I think it may be a while before they find us.
你和别人不同，尼克
You're kind of different, Nick.
Like your dad.
就像你爸爸
我们没什么不同的
We're not all that different.
你是的
Yeah, you are.
But when you think about it...
不过话又说回来了...
我猜这个世界上需要不同的人
I guess the world needs people
who are different.
人们看问题的方法不同
可以这样说
People who see things a little
differently, I guess you could say.
We'll appear sometime
Maybe tonight is yours and mine...
他们都好吗?
都没事，我想再给他们几分钟
Are they okay?
- Yep. I think we better give 'em...
...a couple of minutes though.
那个东西你打算怎么处理?
What are we gonna do about that?
- Adam, look.
亚当 你看
大，大兔子
Big, Big, Big Bunny.
我们该拿这东西怎么办？
What are we gonna do with this?
别担心，我会有办法的，我不是一直都有吗？
Don't worry. I'll think of something.
Don't I always?
- 你不相信我吗?
- 我不知道，我不知道
Don't you trust me?
- I don't know. I don't know.
字幕时间轴:Panzer4h